Guide to the W. H. Taylor Collection, 1837-1938 JL007
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
W. H. Taylor Collection,
1837-1938
JL007
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
96.0 Linear feet
Taylor, W. H.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
The W. H. Taylor Collection consists of records of a general merchandise store in North Bloomfield, Nevada County, California, and records of various other mercantile and mining establishtments in California which apparently were not collected by Taylor, but are included because of their similar or miscellaneous nature.
The North Bloomfield records cover the years 1862-1936. The store was established in 1852, presumably by Donald R. McKillican although there is no actual verification of that fact in this collection. The name of the McKillican store changed several times between the period of 1872 and 1898. An inventory book in the collection is in the name of McKillican Burt, 1872; from an indefinite year until 1890 it was Crandall and McKillican, when it became the Estate of D.R. McKillican; and in 1898, the store was called McKillican and Mobley, probably until its dissolution. D.R. McKillican died in 1892, and much of the correspondence in the collection deals with the settlement of his estate, which didn't actually take place until 1898.
The collection includes paper (correspondence, agreements, legal documents) and samples of various forms, checks, daily account books and inventories (1871-1917); general accounts (journals, daybooks, cash books, ledgers, trial balances, checkbooks) (1862-1936); purchasing, receiving, and production records (order books, sales books, invoices and vouchers) (1870-1908); and a few records of several other companies that were collected by Taylor (1872-1893). The records of other mercantile establishments and miscellaneous volumes comprise the rest of this collection (1837-1924). They include such companies as the Weaverville Supply Company, in Weaverville, Trinity County, California; Blake and Reed Company, also in Weaverville; Dolley's Store in Sierraville, California; and Frazer & Co. in Palo Alto, California, as well as several others. These records are all bound, and although not marked as part of the Taylor collection, many of the establishments that they represent are quite similar to the North Bloomfield operation, in location as well as type of business.
The series of miscellaneous volumes contains records that do not indicate to which business they belong, nor to which collection. They are listed by type of record and then by date (1865-1938). There are certain instances of books of a certain type falling into a consecutive series and being obviously part of the same collection, but they are considered miscellaneous because their identity has not been determined.
For most of these other business records there is no record of the donor, or how they came to Stanford University. Even though these records are unidentified and often non-consecutive, they provide an interesting and valuable source of information about early California merchandising practices. Coupled with the more complete and coherent records of the North Bloomfield store and the other establishments, the Taylor collection presents a good picture of mining town mercantile establishments.
BIOGRAPHY
W.H. Taylor, for whom this collection is named, was a San Mateo, California, resident at the time of his gift, and was with W. H. Taylor & Co., Ltd., Investment Securities, in San Francisco.
Provenance:
Gift of W. H. Taylor (North Bloomfield material), 1940. Gift of George D. Lyman (Weatherbee and Cook Lumber Dealers, and Chysopolis Company material). Gift of Paul E. Holden (account book of W. Williams).
Access Restrictions:
None.
- SERIES A. PAPERS AND SAMPLES, 1871-1917
  Arrangement note
  Items are arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents note
  PAPERS AND SAMPLES includes correspondence, legal documents, and samples of the various forms, checks, statements, etc. used by the company. Also included in this series are samples of daily petty cash books, order, inventory, memo, and time booklets, listed together because of their similar form. They are daily accounts, and are recorded in larger, more permanent volumes, but these have been preserved because of their very nature of being daily accounts.
- SERIES B. GENERAL ACCOUNTS, 1862-1936
  The volumes are arranged chronologically within each record type.
  GENERAL ACCOUNTS includes journals, daybooks, cash books, ledgers, trial balances, receipts and disbursements, checkbooks, and records of checks.
- SERIES C. PURCHASING, RECEIVING, AND PRODUCTION RECORDS, 1870-1908
  Arranged chronologically.
  PURCHASING, RECEIVING, AND PRODUCTION RECORDS includes order books, sales books, invoices, and vouchers.
- SERIES D. RECORDS OF ADDITIONAL COMPANIES AND MISCELLANEOUS VOLUMES IN THE TAYLOR COLLECTION, 1872-1893
  RECORDS OF ADDITIONAL COMPANIES AND MISCELLANEOUS VOLUMES IN THE TAYLOR COLLECTION include several volumes of the Relief Hill mining camp store, the Gold Canyon Quartz Mining Company and the Gold Canyon Mining Company of North Bloomfield, the Yuba Gravel Mining Company of San Francisco, and miscellaneous volumes belonging to the W.H. Taylor collection.
- SERIES E. RECORDS OF OTHER MERCANTILE ESTABLISHMENTS APPARENTLY NOT PART OF THE TAYLOR COLLECTION, (1837-1924)
  RECORDS OF OTHER MERCANTILE ESTABLISHMENTS APPARENTLY NOT PART OF THE TAYLOR COLLECTION include some records of the following companies:
  (233-236) WEAVERVILLE SUPPLY COMPANY
  (236a-239) BLAKE & REED COMPANY
  (240-242) MCNEAR & BROS.
  (243-246) DOLLEY'S STORE
  (247-249) WEATHERBEE AND COOK, LUMBER DEALERS
  (250) CHYSOPOLIS COMPANY
  (251-256) FRAZER & COMPANY
  (257) W. WILLIAMS
  (258) J. SORROUS
- SERIES F. MISCELLANEOUS BUSINESS RECORDS, 1865-1938
  MISCELLANEOUS BUSINESS RECORDS include general account books (journals, cash books, ledgers, daybooks, credit books) and purchase records, order books, and remittance registers. Several of the volumes are stamped with initials of companies, but the full name or location of these companies has not yet been determined.
- SERIES A. PAPERS AND SAMPLES, 1871-1917
  - Legal documents, 1871-1906 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Agreements
    - Tax forms
  - Correspondence regarding D.R. McKillican estate and sundry business correspondence., 1871-1890 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence regarding death of D.R. McKillican and settlement of his estate and some sundry correspondence., 1891-1898 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - National Mine, 1882-1890 (Box 1, Folder 3a)
    - Account
    - Time records
  - Statements: samples, and Indebtedness sheets: samples, 1887-1890; 1889 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bank statements: samples (Agency Nevada County Bank, and Money receipt book: sample, 1911; 1912 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Collection book, Agency Nevada County Bank, 1908-10 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Checks: samples, 1885-1917 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Eureka Express Company: (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - samples, 1872-[1879?]
    - Record of articles transferred 1872-1873
    - Statements, and express tags, Jan-July [1879?]
  - Moore's Flat and Eureka Express Way-bills, sampled March, June, September, and December of the above years., 1876-1878. (Box 2)
  - Petty cash books and cash books: samples, 1884-1891 (Box 2)
  - Order booklets: samples, 1878-1887 (Box 2)
  - Memoranda: samples, [1889?] (Box 2)
  - Tag booklets, 1888-1889 (Box 3)
  - Stamps cancelled booklets, 1891-1892 (Box 3)
  - Remittances, 1898 and 1903 (Box 3)
  - D.R. McKillican's private order booklets, 1886-1887 (Box 3)
  - Deposit accounts, 1883 (Box 3)
  - Malakoff order books, (small mining town near north Bloomfield), 1903-1904 (Box 3)
  - Relief Hill order books, (mining town, three miles from North Bloomfield), 1886-[l900?] (Box 3)
  - Relief Hill order books, 1900-1914 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous account books: samples, 1872-1887 (Box 4)
  - Bank books, 1904-1907 (Box 4)
  - Time books, 1871-1887 (Box 4)
  - Inventory booklets, 1884-1887 (Box 4)
  - Inventory sheets, 1884, 1885, and 1887 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Inventory book, 1872 (Box 5)
  - Inventory book, 1892 (Box 5)
  - Receipts: samples (Box 5)
    - Sept-Dec 1883
    - Jan-Dec 1884
  - Receipts: samples (Box 6)
    - Feb-Dec 1885
    - Jan-May 1886
  - Receipts: samples (Box 7)
    - June-Dec 1886
    - Jan-June 1887
  - Receipts: samples (Box 8)
    - August 1887
    - Nov-Dec 1887
  - Short account book, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Stock book, Jan 1908 (Box 8)
  - Stock book, Jan 1909 (Box 8)
  - Stock book, Jan 1910 (Box 8)
  - Letter copybook, 1901-1902 (Box 8)
- SERIES B. GENERAL ACCOUNTS, 1862-1936
  - Journal, 1870-1871 (Box 9)
  - Journal, 1873 Jan-July (Box 10)
  - Journal, 1873-1874 (Box 11)
  - Journal, April-Nov 1875 (Box 12)
  - Journal, Nov 1875-May 1876 (Box 13)
  - Journal, May-Oct 1876 (Box 14)
  - Journal, Oct 1876-April 1877 (Box 15)
  - Journal, April-Aug 1877 (Box 16)
  - Journal, Aug 1877-Jan 1878 (Box 17)
  - Journal, Jan-June 1878 (Box 18)
  - Journal, June-Nov 1878 (Box 19)
  - Journal, Nov 1878-April 1879 (Box 20)
  - Journal, Aug-Nov 1879 (Box 21)
  - Journal, Dec 1879-July 1880 (Box 22)
  - Journal July 1880-Jan l88l (Box 23)
  - Journal, Jan 1881-Dec 1882 (Box 24)
  - Journal, Dec 1882-Aug 1883 (Box 25)
  - Journal, Sept 1883-Jan 1884 (Box 26)
  - Journal, Feb-Nov 1884 (Box 27)
  - Journal, Nov 1884-Sept 1885 (Box 28)
  - Journal, Sept 1885-June 1886 (Box 29)
  - Journal, June 1886-Jan 1887 (Box 30)
  - Journal, Feb-July 1887 (Box 31)
  - Journal, July-Aug 1887 (Box 32)
  - Journal, Feb 1888-Jan 1895 (Box 33)
  - Journal, 1895-1898 (Box 33a)
  - Journal, 1899-1903 (Box 33b)
  - Journal, 1903-1912 (Box 34)
  - Journal, 1906-1909 (Box 35)
  - Journal, 1909-1912 (Box 36)
  - Journal, 1913-1925 (Box 37)
  - Dry Goods journal, 1933-1936 (Box 38)
  - Supply journal, 1934 (Box 38)
  - Supply journal, 1935 (Box 38)
  - Supply journal, 1936 (Box 38)
  - "Gent's" Journals, Jan 1907-April 1908 (Box 39)
  - "Gent's" Journals, April 1908-May 1909 (Box 39)
  - "Gent's" Journals, May 1909-Dec 1909 (Box 39)
  - Daybook, 1862-June 1870 (Box 40)
  - Daybook, Nov 1870-May 1871 (Box 41)
  - Daybook, Sept 1871-March 1872 (Box 42)
  - Daybook, Aug-Oct 1873 (Box 42)
  - Daybook, Oct-Nov 1873 (Box 42)
  - Daybook, April-June 1874 (Box 42)
  - Daybook, June-Aug 1874 (Box 42)
  - Daybook, Sept l874-Jan 1875 (Box 42)
  - Daybook, Jan-June 1875 (Box 42)
  - Daybook, June-Sept 1875 (Box 43)
  - Daybook, Sept 1875-Jan 1876 (Box 43)
  - Daybook, Jan-June 1876 (Box 43)
  - Daybook, June-Sept 1876 (Box 43)
  - Daybook, Sept 1876-Jan 1877 (Box 43)
  - Daybook, June-Sept 1877 (Box 44)
  - Daybook, Sept-Nov 1877 (Box 44)
  - Daybook, Nov 1877-March 1878 (Box 44)
  - Daybook, March-June 1878 (Box 44)
  - Daybook, June-Aug 1878 (Box 44)
  - Daybook, Aug-Nov 1878 (Box 45)
  - Daybook, Nov 1878-April 1879 (Box 45)
  - Daybook, April-July 1879 (Box 45)
  - Daybook, Aug-Oct 1879 (Box 45)
  - Daybook, Oct-Dec 1879 (Box 45)
  - Daybook, Dec 1879-March 1880 (Box 46)
  - Daybook, March-June 1880 (Box 46)
  - Daybook, June-Aug 1880 (Box 46)
  - Daybook, April 1881-June 1881 (Box 46)
  - Daybook, Oct-Dec 1881 (Box 46)
  - Daybook Dec, 1881-March 1882 (Box 46)
  - Daybook, May-July 1883 (Box 46)
  - Monday-Wednesday-Friday Daybooks
    NOTE: The daybooks from this point up to item number 60 (or between the dates August 1883 and August 1893) were filled in two series; Monday, Wednesday, and Friday; and Tuesday, Thursday, and Saturday. Because the Monday, Wednesday, Friday books correspond more consecutively with each other than with the Tuesday, Thursday, Saturday books for the same period of time, they are arranged separately; first the Monday, etc. books, from August 1883 to December 1892 and then the Tuesday, etc. books from September 1883 to August 1893.
    - Daybook, Aug-Nov 1883 (Box 46)
    - Daybook, Nov 1883-March 1884 (Box 46)
    - Daybook, July-Nov 1884 (Box 46)
    - Daybook, Nov 1884-April 1885 (Box 47)
    - Daybook, April-Aug 1885 (Box 47)
    - Daybook, Aug-Nov 1885 (Box 47)
    - Daybook, Nov 1885-March 1886 (Box 47)
    - Daybook, March-June 1886 (Box 48)
    - Daybook, June-Sept 1886 (Box 48)
    - Daybook, Sept-Dec 1886 (Box 48)
    - Daybook, Dec 1886-Feb 1887 (Box 48)
    - Daybook, Feb-May 1887 (Box 48)
    - Daybook, May-July 1887 (Box 48)
    - Daybook, July-Sept 1887 (Box 49)
    - Daybook, Oct 1887 (Box 49)
    - Daybook, Nov-Dec 1887 (Box 49)
    - Daybook, Dec 1887-Jan 1888 (Box 49)
    - Daybook, Feb-March 1888 (Box 49)
    - Daybook, March-May 1888 (Box 49)
    - Daybook, May-June 1888 (Box 49)
    - Daybook, July-Aug 1888 (Box 49)
    - Daybook, Sept-Dec 1888 (Box 50)
    - Daybook, Dec 1888-Feb 1889 (Box 50)
    - Daybook, Feb-April 1889 (Box 50)
    - Daybook, April-July 1889 (Box 50)
    - Daybook, Jan-Sept 1889 (Box 50)
    - Daybook, Sept-Nov 1889 (Box 50)
    - Daybook, Nov 1889-Feb 1890 (Box 51)
    - Daybook, Feb-April 1890 (Box 51)
    - Daybook, April-June 1890 (Box 51)
    - Daybook, June-Aug 1890 (Box 51)
    - Daybook, Aug-Oct 1890 (Box 51)
    - Daybook, Oct-Dec 1890 (Box 51)
    - Daybook, Dec 1890-March 1891 (Box 51)
    - Daybook, March-May 1891 (Box 51)
    - Daybook, May-July 1891 (Box 51)
    - Daybook, July-Sept 1891 (Box 52)
    - Daybook, Sept-Nov 1891 (Box 52)
    - Daybook, Nov 1891-Feb 1892 (Box 52)
    - Daybook, Feb-April 1892 (Box 52)
    - Daybook, May-Sept 1892 (Box 52)
    - Daybook, Sept-Dec 1892 (Box 52)
  - Tuesday-Thursday-Saturday Daybooks
    - Daybook, Sept-Nov 1883 (Box 53)
    - Daybook, Nov 1883-March 1884 (Box 53)
    - Daybook, March-July 1884 (Box 53)
    - Daybook, July-Nov 1884 (Box 53)
    - Daybook, Nov 1884-April 1885 (Box 53)
    - Daybook, April-Aug 1885 (Box 54A)
    - Daybook, Aug-Nov 1885 (Box 54B)
    - Daybook, Nov 1885-March 1886 (Box 54B)
    - Daybook, March-June 1886 (Box 54B)
    - Daybook, June-Sept 1886 (Box 54B)
    - Daybook, Sept-Dec 1886 (Box 54B)
    - Daybook, Dec 1886-March 1887 (Box 55)
    - Daybook, March-June 1887 (Box 55)
    - Daybook, June-July 1887 (Box 55)
    - Daybook, Aug-Sept 1887 (Box 55)
    - Daybook, Sept-Nov 1887 (Box 55)
    - Daybook, Dec 1887-Jan 1888 (Box 55)
    - Daybook, Feb-March 1888 (Box 56)
    - Daybook, March-May 1888 (Box 56)
    - Daybook, May-July 1888 (Box 56)
    - Daybook, July-Sept 1888 (Box 56)
    - Daybook, Sept-Dec 1888 (Box 56)
    - Daybook, Dec 1888-April 1889 (Box 56)
    - Daybook, April-July 1889 (Box 56)
    - Daybook, July-Sept 1889 (Box 57)
    - Daybook, Sept-Nov 1889 (Box 57)
    - Daybook, Nov 1889 Feb 1890 (Box 57)
    - Daybook, Feb-April 1890 (Box 57)
    - Daybook, April-June 1890 (Box 57)
    - Daybook, June-Aug 1890 (Box 57)
    - Daybook, Aug-Oct 1890 (Box 57)
    - Daybook, Oct-Dec 1890 (Box 57)
    - Daybook, Dec 1890-March 1891 (Box 57)
    - Daybook, March-May 1891 (Box 58)
    - Daybook, May-Aug 1891 (Box 58)
    - Daybook, Aug-Oct 1891 (Box 58)
    - Daybook, Oct-Dec 1891 (Box 58)
    - Daybook, Dec 1891-March 1892 (Box 58)
    - Daybook (single ledger), March-June 1892; and June-Nov 1892 (Box 58A)
    - Daybook, Nov 1892-April 1893 (Box 59)
    - Daybook, May-Aug 1893 (Box 60)
  - Daybook, June 1891-May 1893 (Box 61)
  - Daybook, Oct 1893 (Box 62)
  - Daybook, Nov 1893 (Box 62)
  - Daybook, Dec 1893 (Box 62)
  - Daybook, Jan 1894 (Box 62)
  - Daybook, Feb 1894 (Box 63)
  - Daybook, March 1894 (Box 63)
  - Daybook, April 1894 (Box 63)
  - Daybook, May 1894 (Box 63)
  - Daybook, June 1894 (Box 64)
  - Daybook, July 1894 (Box 64)
  - Daybook, Aug 1894 (Box 64)
  - Daybook, Sept 1894 (Box 64)
  - Daybook, Oct 1894 (Box 64)
  - Daybook, Nov 1894 (Box 64)
  - Daybook, Dec 1894 (Box 65)
  - Daybook, Jan 1895 (Box 65)
  - Daybook, March 1895 (Box 65)
  - Daybook, April 1895 (Box 65)
  - Daybook, May 1895 (Box 65)
  - Daybook, July 1895 (Box 66)
  - Daybook, Aug 1895 (Box 66)
  - Daybook, Sept 1895 (Box 66)
  - Daybook, Oct 1895 (Box 66)
  - Daybook, Nov 1895 (Box 66)
  - Daybook, Dec 1895 (Box 67)
  - Daybook, Feb 1896 (Box 67)
  - Daybook, March 1896 (Box 67)
  - Daybook, April 1896 (Box 67)
  - Daybook, May 1896 (Box 67)
  - Daybook, June 1896 (Box 68)
  - Daybook, July 1896 (Box 68)
  - Daybook, Aug 1896 (Box 68)
  - Daybook, Sept 1896 (Box 68)
  - Daybook, Oct 1896 (Box 69)
  - Daybook, Nov 1896 (Box 69)
  - Daybook, Dec 1896 (Box 69)
  - Daybook, Jan 1897 (Box 69)
  - Daybook, Feb 1897 (Box 69)
  - Daybook, March 1897 (Box 70)
  - Daybook, April 1897 (Box 70)
  - Daybook, May 1897 (Box 70)
  - Daybook, June 1897 (Box 70)
  - Daybook, July 1897 (Box 70)
  - Daybook, Aug 1897 (Box 71)
  - Daybook, Sept 1897 (Box 71)
  - Daybook, Oct 1897 (Box 71)
  - Daybook, Nov 1897 (Box 71)
  - Daybook, Dec 1897 (Box 72)
  - Daybook, Jan 1898 (Box 72)
  - Daybook, Feb 1898 (Box 72)
  - Daybook, March 1898 (Box 72)
  - Daybook, April 1898 (Box 72)
  - Daybook, May 1898 (Box 73)
  - Daybook, June 1898 (Box 73)
  - Daybook, July 1898 (Box 73)
  - Daybook, Aug 1898 (Box 73)
  - Daybook, Sept 1898 (Box 73)
  - Daybook, Oct 1898 (Box 74)
  - Daybook, Nov 1898 (Box 74)
  - Daybook, Dec1898 (Box 74)
  - Daybook, Jan 1899 (Box 74)
  - Daybook, Feb 1899 (Box 74)
  - Daybook, March 1899 (Box 75)
  - Daybook, April 1899 (Box 75)
  - Daybook, May 1899 (Box 75)
  - Daybook, June 1899 (Box 75)
  - Daybook, July 1899 (Box 76)
  - Daybook, Aug 1899 (Box 76)
  - Daybook, Sept 1899 (Box 76)
  - Daybook, Oct 1899 (Box 76)
  - Daybook, Nov 1899 (Box 77)
  - Daybook, Dec 1899 (Box 77)
  - Daybook, Jan 1900 (Box 77)
  - Daybook, Feb 1900 (Box 77)
  - Daybook, March 1900 (Box 77)
  - Daybook, April 1900 (Box 78)
  - Daybook, May 1900 (Box 78)
  - Daybook, June 1900 (Box 78)
  - Daybook, Aug 1900 (Box 79)
  - Daybook, Sept 1900 (Box 80)
  - Daybook, Oct 1900 (Box 81)
  - Daybook, Nov 1900 (Box 82)
  - Daybook, June 1901 (Box 83)
  - Daybook, Feb 1901 (Box 84)
  - Daybook, April-Dec 1901/Jan-March 1902 (Box 84a)
  - Daybook, April-Dec 1902 (Box 84b)
  - Daybook, Jan-June 1903/Aug-Dec 1903 (Box 81c)
  - Daybook, Jan-Aug 1904/0ct-Dec 1904 (Box 84)
  - Daybook, Jan-Oct 1905 (Box 84e)
  - Daybook, Nov-Dec 1905/Jan Aug 1906 (Box 84)
  - Daybook, Sept-Dec 1906/Jan-Aug 1907 (Box 84g)
  - Daybook, Sept-Dec 1907/Jan-April 1908/June-Sept 1908 (Box 84h)
  - Daybook, Oct-Dec 1908/Jan-Dec 1909 (Box 84i)
  - Daybook, Jan-Dec 1910/Jan-May 1911 (Box 84j)
  - Daybook, June-Dec 1911/Jan-Sept 1912 (Box 84k)
  - Daybook, Oct-Dec 1912/Sales 1911-1912/Jan-Oct 1913 (Box 84l)
  - Daybook, Nov-Dec 1913/Stock 1913/Jan-Dec 1914/Stock 1914 (Box 84m)
  - Daybook, Jan-Dec 1915//Stock 1915/Jan-June 1916 (Box 84n)
  - Daybook, July-Dec 1916/Jan-Dec 1917 (Box 84o)
  - Daybook, Jan-Dec 1918/Jan-Dec 1919/Jan-Dec 1920 (Box 84p)
  - Daybook, May-Dec 1920/Jan-Dec 1921/Jan-June 1922/May-Dec 1923 (Box 84q)
  - Daybook, Jan-Dec 1924, 1925/Jan-Aug, Oct-Dec 1926/Jan-Dec 1927, 1928 (Box 84r)
  - Daybook, Jan-Dec 1929,30/Jan-Mar 1931/Oct-Dec 1932/Jan-Dec 1933,1934 (Box 84s)
  - Daybook 2 unidentified, Jan-Dec 1935/March-Dec 1936/Jan-Mar 1937/May 1937, Aug 1937 (Box 84t)
  - Daybook, Aug 1871-March 1872 (Box 85)
    General note
    NOTE: The rest of the daybooks do not belong with the preceeding volumes; they are much larger in addition to containing overlapping dates. For this reason, they are listed at the end of the daybook group.
  - Daybook, Aug 1872-Jan 1873 (Box 86)
  - Daybook, July 1873-Feb 1874 (Box 87)
  - Daybook, Feb-Sept 1874 (Box 88)
  - Daybook, Sept 1874-April 1875 (Box 89)
  - Daybook, April-July 1879 (Box 90)
  - Daybook, Dec 1892-June 1893 (Box 91)
  - Cash book, 1870-1874 (Box 92)
  - Cash book, 1874-1878 (Box 93)
  - Cash book, 1878-1879 (Box 93a)
  - Cash book, 1880-1883 (Box 94)
  - Cash book, 1883 (Box 95)
  - Cash book, 1883-1886 (Box 96)
  - Cash book, 1886-1889 (Box 97)
  - Cash book, 1886-1888 (Box 98)
  - Cash book, 1888-1889 (Box 99)
  - Cash book, 1890-1892 (Box 100)
  - Cash book, 1893-1895 (Box 101)
  - Cash book, 1895-1897 (Box 102)
  - Cash book, 1895-1899 (Box 102a)
  - Cash book, 1898 (Box 103)
  - Cash book, 1899-1904 (Box 104)
  - Cash book, 1900-1903 (Box 105)
  - Cash book, 1904-1906 (Box 106)
  - Cash book, 1904-1909 (Box 107)
  - Cash book, 1909-1913 (Box 108)
  - Cash book, 1913-1918 (Box 109)
  - Cash book, l918-1934 (Box 110)
  - Petty Cash, May 1988-Jan 1889 (Box 111)
  - Petty Cash, Feb-Oct 1889 (Box 111)
  - Petty Cash Oct, 1889-Feb 1891 (Box 111)
  - Petty Cash, March 1891-Nov 1892 (Box 111)
  - Petty Cash, Dec 1892-Aug 1893 (Box 111)
  - Petty Cash, June 1910-May 1911 (Box 111)
  - Petty Cash, June 1912-June 1913 (Box 111)
  - Petty Cash, July 1913-Aug 1914 (Box 111)
  - Petty Cash, Sept 1914-June 1915 (Box 112)
  - Petty Cash, June 1915-Aug 1916 (Box 112)
  - Petty Cash, Sept 1916-Nov 1917 (Box 112)
  - Petty Cash, Nov 1917-April 1919 (Box 112)
  - Petty Cash, May 1919-March 1921 (Box 112)
  - Petty Cash, March 1921-Dec 1922 (Box 112)
  - Receipts and disbursements, Sept 1922-July 1923 (Box 113)
  - Receipts and disbursements, July-Dec 1923 (Box 114)
  - Receipts and disbursements, May 1924-Jan 1925 (Box 115)
  - Index to ledger 1883-1884 (Box 115a)
  - Index to ledger 1885 (Box 116)
  - Index to ledger 1886 (Box 117)
  - Index to ledger 1888 and 1891 (Box 118)
  - Index to ledger 1889 (Box 119)
  - Index to ledger 1892 (Box l20)
  - Index to ledger 1898 (Box 120a)
  - Index to ledger no date (Box 121)
  - Index to ledger no date (Box 122)
  - Index to ledger no date (Box 123)
  - Ledger, 1870-187l (Box 124)
  - Ledger, 1870-1873 (Box 125)
  - Ledger, 1872-1873 (Box 126)
  - Ledger, 1874-1875 (Box 127)
  - Ledger, 1876-1878 (Box 128)
  - Ledger, 1877-1881 (Box 129)
  - Ledger, 1878-1882 (Box 130)
  - Ledger, 1879 (Box 131)
  - Ledger, 1879-1882 (Box 132)
  - Ledger, 1880 (Box 133)
  - Ledger, 1883-1884 (Box 134)
  - Ledger, 1885 (Box 135)
  - Ledger, 1886 (Box l36)
  - Ledger, 1887 (Box 137)
  - Ledger, 1888 (Box 138)
  - Ledger, 1889 (Box 139)
  - Ledger, 1890 (Box 140)
  - Ledger, 1891 (Box 141)
  - Ledger, 1891-1895 (Box 142)
  - Ledger, 1892 (Box 143,)
  - Ledger, 1893-1894 (Box 144)
  - Ledger, 1895-1897 (Box 145)
  - Ledger, 1895-1898 (Box l46)
  - Ledger, 1898 (Box 147)
  - Ledger, 1899-1901 (Box 148)
  - Ledger, 1908-1909 (Box 149)
  - Ledger, n.d. (Box 150)
  - Transfer ledger, 1901-1911 (Box l50a)
  - Transfer ledger, 1913-1925 (Box 150b)
  - Bills, 1895 (Box 151)
  - Record of bills, 1893-1906 (Box 152)
  - Advice, 1931-1938 (Box l53)
  - Trial balance, 1900 (Box 154)
  - Trial balance, 1901-1903 (Box 155)
  - Trial balance, 1903-1905 (Box 156)
  - Trial balance, 1906 (Box 157)
  - Trial balance, 1907 (Box 158)
  - Trial balance, 1908 (Box 159)
  - Trial balance, 1909 (Box 160)
  - Trial balance, 1910 (Box 161)
  - Trial balance, 1911 (Box 162)
  - Trial balance, 1912 (Box 163)
  - Trial balance, 1913 (Box 164)
  - Trial balance, 1915 (Box 165)
  - Trial balance, 1916 (Box 166)
  - Trial balance, 1917 (Box 167)
  - Trial balance, 1919 (Box 168)
  - Trial balance, 1920 (Box 169)
  - Trial balance, 1928 (Box 170)
  - Trial balance, 1933 (Box 171)
  - Trial balance, 1934 (Box 172)
  - Trial balance, n.d. (Box 173-177)
  - Checkboook, 1885-1886 (Box 178)
  - Checkboook, 1886-1887 (Box 179)
  - Checkboook, 1887-1889 (Box 180)
  - Checkboook, 1889 (Box 181)
  - Checkboook, 1890 (Box 182)
  - Checkboook, 1891-1893 (Box 183)
  - Checkboook, 1893-1895 (Box 184)
  - Checkboook, 1895-1897 (Box 184a)
  - Checkboook, 1895-1898 (Box 185)
  - Checkboook, 1899-1901 (Box 186)
  - Checkboook, 1901-1903 (Box 187)
  - Checkboook, 1903-1904 (Box 188)
  - Checkboook, 1904-1905 (Box 189)
  - Checkboook, 1905-1907 (Box 190)
  - Checkboook, 1907 (Box 191)
  - Checkboook, 1907-1908 (Box 192)
  - Checkboook, 1908-1910 (Box 193)
  - Receipts, 1885-1887 (Box 194)
  - Record of checks, 1880-1885 (Box 194)
  - Record of checks, 1885-1889 (Box 194)
  - Record of checks, 1892-1903 (Box 195)
  - Record of checks, 1903-1904 (Box 195)